A Guide to the Papers of William H. Muller, Jr., 1945-2007
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- News release from Medical Center Information Services about Construction beginning of Replacement Hospital, including discharged patient statistics by residence and days of care for July 1983 through June 1984; 1984 November 7, 1 TD (Box-folder 010-014b)
- The New University of Virginia Hospital Ground-Breaking Ceremony; Remarks by Dr. William H. Muller; Key Dates in Hospital construction; Replacement Hospital Ground-Breaking Ceremony: Who, What, When, Where, Why; Cost of Hospital; Patient Care Services; 1984 November 7, 1 program, 5 D (Box-folder 010-014c)
- Ground Breaking Ceremony The New University of Virginia Hospital and Buz Goforth business card; 1984 November 7, title page of photo album, business card (Box-folder 010-015)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-016)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-017)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-018)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-019)
  left to right: Rector Fred G. Pollard, Gov. Charles S. Robb, Pres. Frank L. Hereford, Jr., Dr. William H. Muller, VP for Health Affairs
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-020)
  in back, left to right: Rose Marie Chioni, Dean of the School of Nursing; Norman J. Knorr, Dean of the School of Medicine; Pollard; Robb; Muller
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-021)
  Muller at podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-022)
  Hereford at podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-023)
  Dr. John t. Ashley, Executive Director of the University Hospital next to Rose Marie Chioni; Hereford at podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-024)
  Pollard at podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-025)
  Robb at podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-026)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-027)
  left to right: Robb, Hereford, Muller, Pollard, Knorr, Chioni
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-028)
  Robb, Pollard with shovels, Hereford to the right
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-029)
  Robb, Pollard, Hereford, Muller, Ashley, Chioni, Knorr
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-030)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-031)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-032)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-033)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-034)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-035)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-036)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-037)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-038)
  drawing of building
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-039)
  Ashley, Hereford
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 4 photo (Box-folder 010-040)
  crowd views
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-041)
  Robb, Hereford, Muller on stage
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-042)
  Chioni, Knorr, Pollard, Robb on stage
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-043)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-044)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-045)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-046)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-047)
  Pollard, Robb and Muller leaving podium
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-048)
  Robb with shovel
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-049)
  Pollard and Hereford with shovels
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-050)
  Robb, Pollard, Hereford, Muller, Ashley, Chioni, Knorr with shovels
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 7 photos (Box-folder 010-051)
  Participants with shovels
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-052)
  Ashley, Pollard and Hereford standing by architectural drawing
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 8 photos (Box-folder 010-053)
  main participants and crowd members, post-ceremony?
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 2 photos (Box-folder 010-054)
  architectural models of UVa Medical Center, Hildwin and Willima H. Muller in one photo
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 2 photos (Box-folder 010-055)
  people looking at architectural model, including Mitchell Van Yahres(man on far right in one of the pictures)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, 3 photos (Box-folder 010-056)
- Ground breaking at UVa Hospital; 1984 November 7, photo (Box-folder 010-057)
  Tom Hunter on the left
- Inside UVa: "Governor among honored guests at hospital ceremony1984 November 15, 1 D (Box-folder 010-058)
- The Draw Sheet: "Breaking ground; 1984 December, 1 D (Box-folder 010-059)
- Dr. Muller to Mr. Burgess; 1987 March 23, memo (Box-folder 010-060)
  New hospital dedication
- New Hospital PR Program and Dedication; 1988 February 12, memo (Box-folder 010-061)
- Newsclips from UVa Office of University Relations, New Hospital move-in day coverage; 1989 March 20-23, copies of newspaper clippings (Box-folder 010-061)
- "The Beginning of A New Era, The New University Hospital; 1989, 2 brochures (Box-folder 010-062)
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 1 and 2; 1967-68, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-001)
  Includes clippings from "The Daily Progress" and probably "Medical Alumni News Letter." Names in articles include Jerry Bains, C. Bruce Morton, Leslie Rudolf, Peter Hairston, Gardner W. Smith, J. Shelton Horsley, William Muller.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 3 and 4; 1959, 1967-68, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-002)
  Includes clippings from the "Medical Alumni News Letter" and the "Richmond Times-Dispatch. Names (and some photos) in articles include Jerry Bains, Martha A. Carpenter, Julian R. Beckwith, Richard Rowland Lower, Paul D. Camp, David Milford Hume, and Jack B. Russell. The last five are participants in a Medical Society of Virginia conference on transplantation issues.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 5 and 6; 1968 January 23, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-003)
  "Perspective: Experts Ponder the Transplant Issues" in the "Richmond Times-Dispatch. Names (and some photos) in articles include William Henry Muller, Rev. Reno S. Harp, Rabbi Saul J. Rubin, Howard M McCue, Richard Rowland Lower, and David Milford Hume.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 7 and 8; 1968 January 23, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-004)
  "Perspective: Experts Ponder the Transplant Issues" in the "Richmond Times-Dispatch. Names and some photo) in articles include Howard McCue, Beverly Ordndorff, Sual J. Rubin, William Henry Muller, Julian R Beckwith, Richard Rowland Lower, Jack B. Russell, Reno S. Harp, Paul D. Camp, and David Milford Hume.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 9 and 10; 1968 January 23, ?, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-005)
  Includes the end of the conference as well as an article in which Owen H. Wangensteen discusses the tranplant field and scorns a proposal to establish a commission on the moral, legal and ethical aspects of modern medicine.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 11 and 12; 1968, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-006)
  Includes clippings from "The Daily Progress" and the "Draw Sheet." Articles include one about transplantation and Owen Wangensteen and Stephen Wangensteen; Medical School lectures at Wincester; the new intern staff; and spring medical school lecture series. Bains, Carpenter and Horsley are mentioned.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 13 and 14; 1967-68, photo, clippings (Box-folder 011-007)
  Photo of Surgery Department including House Staff, 1967-68; names on sheet are Minor, Burnett, Rudolf, Callard, Muller, Zug, Morton, Mandel, Drash, Alrich, Horsley, Wangensteen, Bains, Sandusky, Smith, Hakinson, Wright, Maddew, Ramitscher, Kelly, Moore, Ludwig, Hutch, Allport, Jeans, Golden, Wray, Coyne, Ferguson, Milko, Pickles, Prioteau, Herbst, and Stecker. Articles from the "Draw Sheet" include information about James B. Littlefield, J. Shelton Horsley, Gardner W. Smith, William Bobo, William F. Burnett, George M. Callard, and Richard C. Zug.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 15 and 16; 1968, clippings (Box-folder 011-008)
  Clippings from "The Daily Progress" and others. Includes articles about Leslie Rudolf speaking about emergency service and staff shortages, and the Veterans Administration Hospital in Salem. arm
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 17 and 18; 1968, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-009)
  Articles, at least one from "The Daily Progress," concerning the Salem VA Hospital; William Franklin Burnett; new residents including Edgar Allport and Creighton B. Wright; and John W. Kirklin.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 19 and 20; 1969, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-010)
  Articles are about Denton Cooley who lectured at UVa.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 21 and 22; n.d., clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-011)
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 23 and 24; 1969, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-012)
  One article is about Denton Cooley who lectured at UVa. Others about Muller, Sandusky, and the opening of a facial defects clinic established by Jerry Bains.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 25 and 26; 1969, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-013)
  Articles from "The Daily Progress" are about E. Cato Drash and William Muller. A page from "Clinical Congress News" has an article about Muller.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 27 and 28; 1969-70, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-014)
  Articles from "The Daily Progress" and other publications about Francis L. Brochu, UVa in Computer Kidney Exchange, Leslie E. Rudolf, Jerry Bains, Stephen Wangensteen, and Muller.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 29 and 30; 1969-70, photo, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-015)
  Surgery Department photo with House Staff, 1969-70. Names included are Drash, Morton, Wellons, Rawitsher, Muller, Wright, Wray, Sandusky, Nolan, Williams, Wangensteen, Horsley, Rudolf, Minor, Rawitzer, Botero, Segis, Allport, Strauch, Polito, Scruggs, Prioleaus, Starling. "The Daily Progress" article on a device to keep babies warm and Anthony Shaw.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 31 and 32; 1970, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-016)
  Article from "The Daily Progress" about three retiring professors: Edwin W. Burton, E. Cato Drash and C. Bruce Morton; a sex change cliniic; and Milton T. Edgerton and face construction.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 33 and 34; 1970-72, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-017)
  Notes and clippings on the baby warming device which Anthony Shaw helped develop; clippings from UVa Alumni News about Muller; "The Daily Progress" clippings about Wagensteen and Lefer's work on a protein fragment and shock.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 35 and 36; 1971, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-018)
  "Shock: A Common Factor" in "Medical world News" with Allan Lefer and Stephen Wangensteen. also an article from "The Daily Progress" on a thermograph unit and Theodore E. Keats and J. Shelton Horsley.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 37 and 38; 1971-72, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-019)
  Articles are from "The Cavalier Daily," "The Daily Progress" and unknown. Includes articles about J. Shelton Horsley, William H. Muller, and M.C. Wilhelm.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 39 and 40; 1971, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-020)
  Articles are from "The Daily Progress" and probably UVa "Medical Alumni News Letter." Articles are about William H. Muller, E. Meredith Alrich, and Leslie Rudolf and health careers presentation.
- Surgery Department, University of Virginia Medical Center Scrapbook, pages 41 and 42; 1972, clippings with photos (Box-folder 011-021)
  Articles are about donating kidneys, Leslie Rudolf, and Fred Westervelt; and Shelton Horsley.
- Architectural elevation drawing of medical center area; 1987 December 4, elevation drawing (Box-folder 011-022)
  Drawing includes McKim Hall, the Lawn, Health Sciences Library, Jordan Hall, Primary Care Center, Replacement Hospital, several roads and the railroad.
- Proposal for the University of Virginia: Start to Finish; 1982-1989, 2 photos (copied) (Box-folder VAULT 012-001)
  Images from front and back covers and spine of disassembled notebook showing the progress of the construction of the 1989 UVa Hospital.
- Area before and after 1989 UVa Hospital construction; 1985 August-1987 (?), 6 photos (copied) (Box-folder VAULT 012-002)
  includes image of architect mode
- 1989 UVa Hospital construction, 1961 hospital, notebook pages 1 and 2; 1982 November 5 - 1985 October, 39 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-003)
- 1989 UVa Hospital construction and environs, notebook pages 3 and 4; 1985 October - November 19, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-004)
- 1989 UVa Hospital construction and environs, notebook pages 5 and 6; 1985 November 19 - 1986 January 6, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-005)
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 7 and 8; 1986 January 6 - February 25, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-006)
- 1989 UVa Hospital, 1961 Hospital and environs, notebook pages 9 and 10; 1986 February 25 - March 26, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-007)
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, 1961 Hospital, notebook pages 11 and 12; 1986 March 26 - May 28, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-008)
  also includes Old Medical School, overview of Medical Center complex
- 1989 UVa Hospital, 1961 Hospital and environs, notebook pages 13 and 14; 1986 May 28 - July 17, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-009)
  Includes demolition of Interns Building
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 15 and 16; 1986 July 17 - August 25, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-010)
  Dr. Muller and others, tree 'topping' ceremony to mark the highest part of the building
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 17 and 18; 1986 August 25 - November 19, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-011)
  Includes overview of Medical Center complex
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 19 and 20; 1986 November 19 - 1987 January, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-012)
  Includes overview of Medical Center complex, University of Virginia, the lawn
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 21 and 22; 1987 January - April 21, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-013)
  Includes overview of Medical Center complex, University of Virginia grounds
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 23 and 24; 1987 April 21 - October 12, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-014)
- 1989 UVa Hospital and environs, notebook pages 25 and 26; 1987 October 12 -1988 September 20, 40 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-015)
  Includes Medical Center complex
- 1989 UVa Hospital, notebook pages 27 and 28; 1988 September 20 -1989 October 4, 28 slides (Box-folder VAULT 012-016)
  Includes articles about 1961 Hospital from UVa Med Alumni Newsletter, 1960-1961